

# Karina Macancela

## Full Stack Software Developer



## **Summary**

I am a Full-Stack Developer with 2+ years of experience in building Java applications. I am adept at handling strict timelines while maintaining rapport with other developers in a Scrum/Agile environment to fulfill requirements. Besides Java, I have worked with various technologies including Spring, Bootstrap, Hibernate, SQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and Swift. In addition to development, I have experience in project management and have worked with various capability patterns, DevOps, and the business/financial aspects of projects.



## **Experience**

04/2017 - present

#### **Senior Associate**

Infosys Limited - U.S.A.

- I have been working closely with clients on-site as a software consultant.
- I worked with well-known health insurance company, Aetna, for two years as a software developer and project manager. This allowed me to get experience in developing and managing projects from start to finish.
- I was trained extensively in both roles. Meanwhile, I continuously communicate and organize with our offshore team.

02/2018 -05/2019

### **Associate Project Manager / Domain Lead**

Aetna - Hartford, CT

- Coordinated with project managers and stakeholders to track project scope, schedule, and cost.
- Assisted Project Managers in preparing the project financials such as labor and non-labor budget reports, major milestones, and forecasting reports.
- Performed activities such as creating audit records, validating approvals, and conducting compliance audits.
- Extensive use of project management tools such as IBM Rational ClearQuest and ClearCase, Intuit QuickBase, PlanView, and SAP BI Launchpad.

06/2017 -02/2018

#### **Associate Software Developer**

Aetna - Hartford, CT

- Developed, tested, and supported various APIs for different consumers based on their requirements using IBM API Connect.
- Utilized Splunk to check logs for errors in order to debug API failures.
- Worked closely with the DevOps team to create an automated and faster way to deploy APIs.
- Coordinated with offshore talent to gather requirements from consumers for API development.
- Utilized Git to upload completed APIs to the companies private repository so the DevOps team could automate its deployment into testing environments.



#### E-mail

karymacancela@gmail.com

#### Website

https://kmacancela.github.io

#### **GitHub (Projects)**

https://github.com/kmacancela

#### LinkedIn

https://linkedin.com/in/kmacancela



## Languages

Java

HTML & CSS

JavaScript

SQL

Swift



### Skills

**Spring** 

Hibernate

Microservices

Object Relational Mapping

Bootstrap

**Project Management** 

Agile Methodology

DevOps



## **Software**

Eclipse

IntelliJ IDEA

Xcode

Oracle Database

MySQL

Git

Jenkins

Adobe Photoshop

Sony Vegas Pro

#### 11/2016 -04/2017

### Full Stack Developer

Revature - Flushing, NY

- Used HTTP Servlet to handle GET and POST requests.
- Created a Business Delegate to build a bridge between business logic and backend.
- Incorporated POJO Java beans to work with a SQL relational database.
- Used JDBC to allow clients to access the database.
- Used ORM framework in order to map beans to tables in our relational database in SQL Developer.
- Implemented Continuous Integration with project collaborators using Slack and Git.

#### 09/2013 -11/2016

### IT College Assistant

City University of New York - Flushing, NY

- Employee of the Office of Information Technology at Queens College while being a full-time student.
- Supervision and maintenance of the open lab and surrounding classrooms.
- Help desk duties such as assistance with projectors, laptops, smart boards, and re-imaging computers.



## **Education**

### 08/2011 -06/2016

## **Queens College**

City University of New York - Flushing, NY

- Bachelor's in Computer Science with 3.1 GPA
- Bachelor's in Applied Mathematics with 3.4 GPA



## References

References Available Upon Request